This come this will be the last lecture on machine level programming
这将是关于机器级编程的最后一次讲座
We call it advanced topics but think of it more as miscellaneous topics
我们将其称为高级主题，但将其视为杂项主题
And I think most to you of course you know that your bomb lab due tonight
我想你当然最了解你的炸弹实验室今晚到期了
So you most year probably well into that or hopefully through it
所以你大部分时间都可能很好，或希望通过它
And then at midnight tonight the next web will come out which is called attack lab
然后在今晚的午夜，下一个网络将出现，称为攻击实验室
And there is a recitation about that yesterday
昨天有一个关于这个的背诵
But this is a lab that's a new to the course
但这是一个实验室，是课程的新手
It's a similar to one that we used to use at this point in the course
它类似于我们过去在课程中使用的那个
But it's been updated and changed in significant ways
但它已经在很大程度上得到了更新和改变
So we're actually when you have labs like we do in this course with this many students
所以我们实际上就像你在这个课程中有这么多学生一样的实验室
There's a lot of things can go wrong
有很多事情可能会出错
So we're going to keep a close eye on how things are going
因此，我们将密切关注事情的进展
But I'd encourage you you only have a week and a half to do this next lab
但我鼓励你，你只有一个半星期的时间去做下一个实验
To get started soon and partly by having some people start sooner
要尽快开始，部分是让一些人早点开始
You'll start breaking things for us that we can track down
你将开始为我们打破我们可以追踪的事情
So today what we'll talk about is a couple like I said it's miscellaneous topics but important topics
所以今天我们要谈的是一对夫妇，比如我说它是杂项主题，但重要的话题
One is just sort of what does the memory look like when you're running x86-64 programs
一个是运行x86-64程序时内存的样子
The other is a very important topic on security vulnerability called buffer overflows
另一个是关于安全漏洞的非常重要的主题，称为缓冲区溢出
And in fact the attack lab will be precisely exploiting those security vulnerabilities
事实上，攻击实验室将正是利用这些安全漏洞
And then we'll look at unions,so far you've booked it arrays and structs and how they're organized
然后我们会看看工会，到目前为止，你已经预订了数组和结构以及它们是如何组织的
And I want to compare that to unions
我想把它与工会进行比较
So let's talk about memory then as I said at the beginning early in the course
那么就像我在课程开始时所说的那样，让我们​​谈谈内存
Conceptually a memory is just a big array of bytes
从概念上讲，内存只是一个很大的字节数组
And that's the view of this the machine level programmer
这就是机器级程序员的看法
Even though it's not the actual implementation
即使它不是实际的实现
There's a whole part that we'll talk about later in the course
我们将在课程后期讨论整个部分
Of this is called virtual memory
其中称为虚拟内存
This organization is very simple organization
这个组织非常简单
But the underlying implementation is this complex management of
但底层实施是这种复杂的管理
Of various different memory types from disk memories to solid state disks
从磁盘存储器到固态磁盘的各种不同存储器类型
And to what's called DRAM which stands for dynamic RAM the
而所谓的DRAM代表动态RAM
When you buy memory for your processor its DRAM
当你为你的处理器购买内存时它的DRAM
Um so as you know in x86-64 we're working with machines that nominally have addresses can be up to 64 bits long
嗯，你知道在x86-64我们正在使用名义上有地址的机器可以长达64位
And if you work out the numbers remember I told you at the beginning of the course
如果你算出数字，记得我在课程开始时告诉过你
You can estimate how big a number like to the 64 is by remembering that 1024
你可以通过记住1024来估计与64相似的数字
And a thousand are very close to each other
千人彼此非常接近
So 2^10 is roughly the same as 10^3
因此2 ^ 10与10 ^ 3大致相同
So you take 64 and you think 60
所以你拿64，你认为60
So how big is 2^60 well that's 6*10 and therefore it's 6*3,it's like 10^18
那么2 ^ 60井有多大6 * 10因此它是6 * 3，就像10 ^ 18
And then you add the four to that that's 2^4 and 16
然后你将四个加到2 ^ 4和16
So it's around 16*10^18 bytes
所以它大约是16 * 10 ^ 18字节
So if you were to go off and look online on amazon for DRAM chips
所以，如果你想在亚马逊网上看看DRAM芯片
And try to buy that much memory you'd find you're spending a lot of money
并尝试购买那么多内存，你会发现你花了很多钱
More than you I don't know the numbers but it would be a lot of memory money
比你更多我不知道数字，但它会有很多记忆金
And so you basically can't do it nowadays
所以你现在基本上不能这样做
Tend to the and so...
倾向于等...
Right now the machines limit you to actually only 47 bits worth of address in the address space
现在，机器限制你在地址空间中实际只有47位的地址
I'll and so 2^47 again work that out that's like 256*10^12
我会这样2 ^ 47再次工作，那就像256 * 10 ^ 12
So it's 256 terabytes
所以它是256太字节
And as you know you can buy a disk drive now that has 8 terabytes
如你所知，你现在可以买一个8TB的磁盘驱动器
So it doesn't seem like that much
所以看起来并不那么多
But if you tried to buy that much DRAM again you'd have to have a pretty big credit-card limit
但如果你再次尝试购买那么多的DRAM，你必须有一个非常大的信用卡限制
And so even that's a huge number and modern super computer installations actually will have almost that much memory
因此，即使这是一个庞大的数字和现代超级计算机安装实际上将有几乎那么多的记忆
But the point is that the hardware of today limits you to 47 bits worth of address
但问题是，今天的硬件限制了你的47位地址
But that's not really a real limitation in terms of of of actual machines
但就实际机器而言，这并不是真正的限制
And what will happen is memory prices get cheaper and the technology gets better
会发生什么是内存价格变得更便宜，技术变得更好
They'll slowly start adding as succeeding generations of processors come along
随着后续几代处理器的出现，它们将慢慢开始添加
Let you have bigger and bigger range of addresses
让你拥有越来越大的地址范围
So all that is to say that's why
所有这就是说这就是原因
This number shows up which is a seven followed by eleven Fs
这个数字显示为7，然后是11个Fs
I can tell I need to scribble some numbers you guys
我可以说我需要给你们一些数字
Just saying numbers in the air is not working here
只是说空中的数字在这里不起作用
So let's try
让我们试试吧
Ok
好
Okay so remember I said before to 2^64 is about equal to 16*10^18
好吧所以记得我之前说过2 ^ 64大约相当于16 * 10 ^ 18
And 2^47 is 128*10^12
并且2 ^ 47是128 * 10 ^ 12
So it's 128 terabytes
所以这是128太字节
So what's the number after a terabyte you know 10^15
那么你知道10 ^ 15之后的数字是多少
How many but yes petabytes right
多少，但是正确的是petabytes
And you know what 10^18 is
你知道10 ^ 18是什么
So just as a reference a company like google roughly
所以就像谷歌粗略的公司一样参考
It's probably it's total storage across the whole
它可能是整个存储的总存储空间
Enterprise is measured in some small number of x bytes
企业以少量x字节来衡量
And it every day is getting several petabytes I don't know the numbers are of course secret
它每天都有几PB，我不知道这些数字当然是秘密的
But maybe 10 petabytes or more per day of new data that it's ingesting into its system so
但是每天可能会有10 PB或更多的新数据被它摄入到它的系统中
These numbers are pretty huge but not just totally off the charts
这些数字非常巨大，但不仅仅是完全脱离图表
Do you know what 10^21 is? It's called a zettabyte with two t's
你知道10 ^ 21是什么吗？它被称为带有两个t的zettabyte
And it's estimated if you add up all the digital content in the world
据估计，如果你将世界上所有的数字内容加起来
That gets created everybody's cell phone camera every video
每个视频都会创建每个人的手机摄像头
Taken by anyone anywhere all year long is a couple of zettabytes a year
全年任何人都可以使用一年两次的zettabytes
So it'll be a while before we're really having to deal with that kind of memory
所以在我们真正处理这种记忆之前还需要一段时间
So just to give you an idea so 128 terabytes is the address limit on these systems
所以只是为了给你一个想法，所以这些系统的地址限制为128太字节
And so that's why you have to have seven because you remember that's one two three
所以这就是为什么你必须有七个，因为你记得那是一个二三
And then there's f but there's 11 of them and this is 111 times 11
然后有f但是其中有11个，这是111次11
So that's 44 ones and this is three ones
那是44个，这是三个
And that's where you get 47
这就是你得到47的地方
And that's the address of the in Linux
这就是Linux中的地址
That's where they put the stack is up at the very top of the address space
这就是他们把堆栈放在地址空间最顶端的地方
And I should tell you this picture is not at all to scale it would be impossible to draw this picture to scale
而且我应该告诉你，这张照片根本没有按比例绘制，因此无法按照比例绘制这张照片
For example it shows that the stack starts way up at the top
例如，它显示堆栈从顶部开始向上
And remember stacks grow to smaller addresses
并记住堆栈增长到较小的地址
When you're pushing and also we show the them upside down just to make everything confusing
当你在推动时，我们也将它们颠倒过来，只是为了让一切变得混乱
So the the stack starts there and it grows towards lower addresses
所以堆栈从那里开始，它朝着较低的地址增长
And on a typical system it will be limited to 8 megabytes
在典型的系统上，它将限制在8兆字节
And you can tell that on a Linux system at least
你至少可以在Linux系统上说出来
With the the limit command
使用limit命令
Which used to be more interesting than it was is now because a lot of things are unlimited
过去比现在更有趣，因为很多东西都是无限的
But you see it says the stack size is limited to 8192 kbytes or kilobytes
但是你看到它表示堆栈大小限制为8192千字节或千字节
So it's 8 megabytes
所以它是8兆字节
And what that means is if you tried to access any memory via the stack pointer
这意味着如果你试图通过堆栈指针访问任何内存
That was outside of the range of this 8 megabyte range you'd get a segmentation fault
这超出了这个8兆字节范围的范围，你会遇到分段错误
And then down at the lower addresses what comes in what gets put into your program are the parts of the code
然后在较低的地址向下放入程序中的内容是代码的各个部分
That that come out of the executable file
那个来自可执行文件
And so there's a section and we'll talk more,when we talk about linking actually
所以有一个部分，当我们谈论实际链接时，我们会谈得更多
About the way out of the memory and the different regions of it
关于记忆的方式和它的不同区域
But for some obscure reason they call where the code is sitting the executable program the text segment
但是由于一些不明原因，他们称代码位于可执行程序的文本段
I don't know why that's true, but it's the way it is and that's across many machines
我不知道为什么会这样，但它就是它的方式而且是在许多机器上
And then the data is first of all there'll be a section for the data that's allocated at the program begins
然后数据首先会有一个部分用于在程序中分配的数据开始
So any global variables that you've declared will be in that section
因此，你声明的任何全局变量都将出现在该部分中
And then the heap is the part of memory that is x is allocated via call to malloc or one of its related functions
然后堆是内存的一部分，x是通过调用malloc或其相关函数之一来分配的
And so that varies dynamically as the program runs
因此，程序运行时会动态变化
It starts off with a very small allocation and every time you call malloc
它从一个非常小的分配开始，每次你调用malloc
If you're not freeing memory and so your memory requirements keep growing
如果你没有释放内存，那么你的内存需求会不断增长
It will crease keep up moving up larger and larger addresses
它会随着地址越来越大而不断增加
And then somewhere in the code too and this can vary by system is
然后在代码中的某个地方，这可能因系统而异
The code that gets brought in that represents the library functions things like printf and malloc itself
引入的代码表示库函数类似printf和malloc本身
Our own library code they're stored off on disk
我们自己的库代码存储在磁盘上
And they get brought in they get linked into your program
他们被引入，他们被链接到你的程序
When it first starts executing by a process known as dynamic linking
当它首次通过称为动态链接的过程开始执行时
Which we'll talk about later in the course too with the linking
我们将在后面的课程中讨论链接
And what you'll find in general is that
你会发现一般的是
Allocations will tend to be either at these very low addresses
分配将倾向于在这些非常低的地址
Or these very high addresses as your program is running
或者在程序运行时这些非常高的地址
So just as an example here is some code
所以这里只是一些代码
Um that it's only value is to show you different where things get located
嗯它唯一的价值就是向你展示不同的地方
And so you'll see I allocated some a fairly large arrays here
所以你会看到我在这里分配了一些相当大的数组
This one is there all cares but this is 1<<24 so it's 16
这个是关注所有，但这是1 << 24所以它是16
A megabyte array and this one is 1<<31
一个兆字节数组，这个是1 << 31
So it's 2 gigabytes worth of array
所以这是2千兆字节的数组
I found that if I tried to allocate larger ones it the program wouldn't run
我发现如果我试图分配更大的那个程序就不会运行
And I also do some here's just a sort of global variable and here's a function
我也在这里做一些全局变量，这是一个函数
And then there's a single function here with some local variable
然后这里有一个函数，带有一些局部变量
And that will be allocated somewhere on the stack
这将被分配到堆栈的某个地方
And then there's several calls to milk some of which are for some very small chunks of memory
然后有几次调用牛奶，其中一些用于一些非常小的内存
And somewhere for some very large chunks of memory
还有某些非常大的内存块
And so we can run this program and see what addresses pop out of it
所以我们可以运行这个程序，看看它弹出的地址
And what you'll see is the stack
而你会看到的是堆栈
This local variable is somewhere up with an address in the range of the stack
这个局部变量在某个地方有一个堆栈范围内的地址
And you see the 7 and a couple fs and then it goes to something else
你看到7和几个fs然后它去了别的东西
And you'll see also interestingly enough that the code and then looking down at the bottom
而且你会看到有趣的代码然后俯视底部
Of this yellow color is things get relegated to the text segment the main function
这种黄色的东西被降级为文本段的主要功能
And this function I called I declared called useless
而这个函数我叫我声称无用
And then the predefined arrays
然后是预定义的数组
That were in other words globally declared not declared by malloc
换句话说，全局声明不是由malloc声明的
They're declared as part of the program itself are down here in this data section
它们被声明为程序本身的一部分，在此数据部分中
And because it's a very large array, the huge array you actually get some fairly large addresses
而且因为它是一个非常大的数组，你实际上得到了一个相当大的地址
And then interestingly enough
然后有趣的是
Or I don't know why it's interesting but for one reason or another
或者我不知道为什么它有趣但是出于某种原因
It happen that the smaller chunks of memory allocations
它发生在较小的内存分配块上
Are down here at addresses that are actually just a little bit above  the the pink section right
在这里的地址实际上只是粉红色部分的正上方
And similarly the really big chunks of memory I allocate
同样，我分配的内存非常庞大
Are way up here near the stack limit
是在堆栈限制附近的方式
And they are...
他们是......
And so they're there and in general what's happening is if I were to try and reference
所以他们就在那里，总的来说，如果我试着参考的话会发生什么
A memory address in this empty range I'd get a segmentation fault
在这个空范围内的内存地址我会得到一个分段错误
It's a valid address in terms of its bit of properties
就其位属性而言，它是一个有效的地址
But it hasn't actually been set up and allocated by the memory the virtual memory allocator
但它实际上并没有由内存设置和分配虚拟内存分配器
So at any given time the valid addresses
所以在任何给定时间有效地址
Are just those in the lower portion or the upper portion of this address ranges
只是位于此地址范围的下部或上部的那些
And the middle is sort of no-man's land
中间是一种无人的土地
And then what happens is you keep allocating more with malloc
然后会发生什么事情，你继续用malloc分配更多
And it will push the limits of what's addressable in toward it
它将推动可解决的极限
And in principle if you ever got too much of a memory request
原则上，如果你有太多的内存请求
These two would hit each other and you and malik would return zero at that point
这两个会相互碰撞，你和malik会在那时返回零
But it's highly unlikely given that you have 128 terabytes of (memory) address range here
但鉴于此处有128 TB的（内存）地址范围，这种可能性极小
So that just and you've probably seen this when you're running
所以你刚刚跑步时就已经看过这个了
You're looking at disassembled code with GDB
你正在查看使用GDB的反汇编代码
You're seeing some addresses that are way up here with the 7 and some f so they're stack addresses
你看到一些地址在这里与7和一些f，所以他们是堆栈地址
And you see these fours
而且你看到了这些四肢
You know a lot of zeros and some fours those tend to be where the code is going
你知道很多零和四个那些往往是代码的地方
Question
题
Why doesn't the heat proceed in one direction I actually don't know
为什么热量不会沿着我实际上不知道的方向前进
I'll just observe that it was had a strategy of putting big things here in small things here
我只是观察它有一个策略，在这里把小东西放在这里
And it probably uses different slightly different management strategies for those two
它可能会对这两者采用不同的略有不同的管理策略
Okay so that I think you'll find that kind of useful to have some sense when you're looking at
好的，所以我觉得你会发现在你看的时候有一点意义
When you're running GDB it helps to just have some idea of what's going on when you're looking at these different addresses
当你运行GDB时，只需了解一下当你查看这些不同的地址时会发生什么
Okay now let's talk about buffer overflow
好的，现在让我们谈谈缓冲区溢出
And we'll start this you remember on the very first class
我们将在第一堂课时开始记得
And I think we might have reviewed this part way along
我想我们可能已经审查了这一部分
We showed this example of some programs where if you do an out-of-bounds
我们展示了一些程序的例子，如果你做了一个越界
Reference and write a value that's out of bounds in particular
引用并写出特别超出范围的值
I only have a array of two elements here
我这里只有两个元素的数组
But this function will take an arbitrary value of i
但是这个函数将取i的任意值
And assign some magic number to ailment i of the array
并为阵列的疾病i分配一些魔法数字
And it has the possibility of...
它有可能......
And we saw that when you do that
当你这样做时，我们看到了
If I gets too big it will first
如果我变得太大，它将首先
Corrupt the the double that stored is part of the struct
腐蚀存储的双重结构的一部分
And then when it gets bigger it seems to
然后当它变大时，它似乎
Not have any effect until it gets too big and then you start corrupting memory
在它变得太大然后你开始破坏内存之前没有任何影响
So the basic point is that it's very easy in a program, a C program in particular
所以基本点是它在程序中非常容易，特别是C程序
To a reference memory that's not part of the sort of intent of the program
对于不属于程序意图类型的参考存储器
And this can happen in programs that aren't properly written that
这可能发生在没有正确编写的程序中
And it becomes a security vulnerability if there's some way for an outsider to overflow a buffer
如果局外人有一些方法来溢出缓冲区，它就成了一个安全漏洞
For example if there is some way for an outsider to give a larger value of i and ask that
例如，如果局外人有某种方式可以给出更大的i值并且要求它
That value be stored there it could crash the program
该值存储在那里可能导致程序崩溃
And so in general when you write in code you try to think about  can I trust this value
所以一般来说，当你在代码中编写时，你试着想一想我是否可以相信这个价值
This a value that's been computed by my program and I'm sure that it's within bounds
这个值是由我的程序计算出来的，我确信它在界限范围内
Or is it something that's come from an external source
或者它是来自外部来源的东西
And there is potentially that risk of being a vulnerability
并且存在潜在的漏洞风险
And so in particular there's a lot a huge class of errors
特别是有很多错误
That have to do with overflowing buffers where
这与溢出缓冲区有关
Where they're trying to store a string of some type that's been read from a message
他们试图存储从消息中读取的某种类型的字符串
And without knowing in advance how big that string is
并且事先不知道该字符串有多大
It's possible that it will be too big for the buffer that's been allocated
对于已分配的缓冲区，它可能太大了
And so one of the culprits is there's a whole class of library functions that
因此，其中一个罪魁祸首就是有一整套库函数
Let you store something a string somewhere without any kind of bounds checking even being possible
让你在某个地方存储一些字符串，即使可能也没有任何边界检查
So the sort of worst one is one called gets
所以最糟糕的一种叫做获取
And the purpose of gets is normally it's used to read a string from
get的目的通常是用来从中读取字符串
An input from a terminal input something that somebody's typed into a terminal
来自终端的输入输入某人键入终端的内容
And so what it's doing is it's scanning this input string
所以它正在做的是扫描这个输入字符串
And looking for a character that represents the end of the line
并寻找代表该行结束的角色
Which we write in of cea's is backslash n
我们用cea写的是反斜杠n
And it has a character code at hex of 0a
它有一个十六进制的字符代码
And so gets this is sort of an approximate version of what the code for gets looks like
因此得到这是一个近似版本的代码获取的样子
That and it's as an argument it's just given a destination of where to store the result
那就是它作为一个参数，它只是给出了存储结果的目的地
And all it does is it reads one character at a time
它所做的只是一次读取一个字符
Looks for an end-of-file meaning that the input stream is closed or an end-of-line
查找文件结尾意味着输入流已关闭或行尾
But as long as it until it sees that it just keeps adding more things to the end of this buffer
但只要它看到它只是不断添加更多的东西到这个缓冲区的末尾
And so typically
通常如此
When somebody calls gets they'll pass it a pointer to some buffer that they've allocated
当有人调用时，他们会向它传递一个指向他们已分配的缓冲区的指针
But the function and it will just gets we'll just fill that buffer up
但是功能和它只会让我们只填充缓冲区
But it can potentially just keep going there's nothing in the function
但它可能只是继续发挥作用
There's not even an argument to the function
这个功能甚至没有争论
That tells the function when it has to stop When it's reached the limit of it
这告诉函数何时必须停止它何时达到它的极限
So it was written it actually gets is
所以写的它实际得到了
If you try to compile code would gets it will flash up a big warning that says
如果你试图编译代码会得到它会闪现一个大警告说
This is really an unsafe function you probably shouldn't even be using it
这实际上是一个不安全的功能，你甚至可能不应该使用它
Because it was written in the 1970s
因为它写于20世纪70年代
When the early UNIX distributions were coming out
当早期的UNIX发行版问世时
Where people just weren't worried about security vulnerabilities
人们只是不担心安全漏洞
And they just assumed that if you allocated a big enough buffer
他们只是假设你分配了足够大的缓冲区
That there's no reason why a string should be bigger than what you've allocated
没有理由为什么字符串应该大于你分配的字符串
And that's actually true with other functions like strcpy
对于像strcpy这样的其他函数来说，这实际上是正确的
You recall strcpy has two arguments
你记得strcpy有两个参数
Excuse me a destination and a source
对不起，目的地和来源
And its purpose is to copy the string at the source into the destination
其目的是将源头处的字符串复制到目的地
And the way it determines the end of the string and the source is when it hits a null character
它确定字符串结束的方式和源是它命中空字符的方式
That just keeps copying one by one well until it hits it
这只是一个接一个地复制，直到它击中它
But it has no way of knowing there's nothing no information there about how much
但它无法知道没有任何关于多少信息的信息
How big is the the buffer allocated at the destination
在目的地分配的缓冲区有多大
And so it can easily overrun that
所以它很容易超支
That a similar one called strcat which is used to concatenate two strings copy another destination
类似的一个名为strcat，用于连接两个字符串复制另一个目标
And the scanf functions also have possible in the format string
scanf函数也可以在格式字符串中使用
You can give the %s
你可以给％s
A directive to the format string which says read in a string and store it someplace
指向格式字符串的指令，该字符串表示读取字符串并将其存储在某个位置
And it doesn't say how long the string is limited to be
并且它没有说明字符串被限制为多长时间
And it doesn't say how much memory is available at the destination
并没有说目的地有多少内存可用
So again it can easily just write over that a buffer
因此，它可以轻松地写入缓冲区
So these are real vulnerabilities and they we'll talk in a minute a little later about
所以这些都是真正的漏洞，我们稍后会谈一会儿
How you as a programmer can be a little smarter than this
作为一名程序员，你如何比这更聪明
But in their suit of raw form as presented they have this vulnerability to them
但是在他们提出的原始形式的诉讼中，他们对他们有这种脆弱性
So let's look at an example of what this can...what can happen there
那么让我们看一下这可以做什么的例子......那里会发生什么
So imagine for example we want a to implement echo function
所以想象一下，例如我们想要实现echo函数
So an echo function is one that you just type something in and prints it back out
因此，echo函数是你只需输入内容并将其打印出来的函数
It's very uninteresting function except it's very useful to demonstrate things
这是非常无趣的功能，除了它展示事物非常有用
So the idea is it has this little buffer it's only enough to hold four characters
所以这个想法是它有这个小缓冲区，它只能容纳四个字符
Because get us to read a string from the input and then it calls puts
因为让我们从输入中读取一个字符串然后调用puts
Which simply writes back out the output
这只是简单地写回输出
And
和
And so let me just demo this not very interesting function
所以让我演示这个不是很有趣的功能
So I call here buffdemo-nsp
所以我在这里叫buffdemo-nsp
Meaning as no stack protector we'll see in a minute what a stack protector is
意思是没有堆栈保护器我们会在一分钟内看到堆栈保护器是什么
But you see if you type a reasonably strong small string
但是你看是否输入了一个相当强大的小字符串
Let's see what remember it can handle more than four
让我们看看它能处理四个以上的东西
Actually as written it can't handle more than three right
实际上，正如所写，它不能处理超过三个权利
Because there should be room for the null character to on terminator
因为在终结符上应该有空字符的空间
So it turns out with this particular one if I type in a string of 24 characters
因此，如果我输入一个包含24个字符的字符串，则会发现这个特定的一个
It'll be okay
没关系
But if I type in a string of 24 characters
但是如果我输入一个24个字符的字符串
It will hit a segmentation fault
它会遇到分段错误
So where do those numbers 23 and 24 come in
那么23号和24号的位置在哪里呢？
Well that's something we can learn by looking at the assembly code
那么我们可以通过查看汇编代码来学习
So here's and we'll go through this code
所以这里，我们将通过这段代码
So first of all, this is the code for echo then
首先，这是echo的代码
And you see the echo calls gets and it calls puts
你看到echo调用得到它并调用puts
And here's the part of the code where you can tell how much memory got allocated for the buffer
这里是代码的一部分，你可以告诉我们为缓冲区分配了多少内存
And 0x18 is what in decimal
而0x18是十进制的
24 right?
24对吗？
And just saw that the thing actually segfaults with a input string of 24
只是看到这个东西实际上是一个输入字符串为24的段错误
So we'll see that in a minute
所以我们会在一分钟内看到
But anyways you can see here that it's allocating on the stack a region of 24 bytes
但无论如何你可以在这里看到它在堆栈上分配一个24字节的区域
And it's copying that into %rdi which is of course the argument for gets
它正在将其复制到％rdi中，这当然是获取的参数
So gets is being called with a pointer to a buffer of size 24 of maximum 24
因此，使用指向最大24的大小为24的缓冲区的指针调用gets
Or even though you saw the original declaration was just four
或者即使你看到原始声明只有四个
Um and then it calls gets and then gets does it thing
嗯然后它调用得到然后得到它做的事情
And just one last little bit to keep in mind is
最后一点要记住的是
We'll get back to them
我们会回复他们
Oh yes and remember echo
哦，是的，记得回声
I there's a function called call_echo which is the thing that calls echo
我有一个名为call_echo的函数，它调用echo
And just to keep in mind this red is the return address  for call_echo
并且要记住这个红色是call_echo的返回地址
And that's going to be important
这将是重要的
So what we see then is the memory layout is
所以我们看到的是内存布局
The buff is normally big enough for four characters
buff通常足以容纳四个字符
There's a sort of 20 bytes of unused or wasted space here
这里有20个字节的未使用或浪费的空间
And then the actual return address which is the return address for back to call_echo is stored on the stack
然后将实际返回地址（返回call_echo的返回地址）存储在堆栈中
So when this program begins running when echo starts to run
所以当这个程序开始运行时，echo开始运行
We'll find that this is the value on the stack for the return pointer
我们会发现这是返回指针的堆栈值
And if we type in a string of up here of 23 characters
如果我们输入一个23个字符的字符串
You'll see that it uses up this entire buffer and remember a string is terminated with 00
你会看到它耗尽了整个缓冲区并记住字符串以00结尾
But it still hasn't...it's still within the region that was allocated on the stack for that
但它仍然没有...它仍然在为堆栈分配的区域内
So it just barely fits into the the stack
所以它几乎不适合堆栈
And that's why we technically we overflowed the buffer
这就是为什么我们在技术上会溢出缓冲区
But we didn't really cause any harm because there was this extra space available
但是我们并没有真正造成任何伤害，因为有这个额外的空间可用
And so that's why I could type in that string of 23 characters and it worked fine
这就是为什么我可以键入23个字符的字符串，它工作正常
But now if I type in...
但现在如果我输入...
This is an example showing...
这是一个显示......的例子
I actually 25 characters
我实际上是25个字符
So once I go beyond the 23 characters plus the null character you'll see
所以，一旦我超越了23个字符加上你将看到的空字符
what I'm slowly starting to do is corrupt the the the byte representation of the return address
我正在慢慢开始做的是破坏返回地址的字节表示
And so what happens for example here
所以这里发生了什么
Is that rather than trying to return back to the where call_echo was supposed to where it was supposed to go back to
是不是试图回到call_echo所应该回到的地方
It goes back to some other part of your code
它可以追溯到代码的其他部分
That may or may not be a valid address or
这可能是也可能不是有效的地址或
Might not have anything to do with the program you're trying to run
可能与你尝试运行的程序无关
So this example shows it and if I typed in the 24
所以这个例子显示了它，如果我输入24
Let's see...before I got it to run
在我开始运行之前，让我们看看......
Like this you know this thing depends on the what happens
像这样你知道这件事取决于发生了什么
How the code happens to get compiled
如何编译代码
Oh yeah so okay, so actually you see here
哦，是的，所以你真的看到了这里
This first string I typed is actually 24 characters long plus the null pointer
我输入的第一个字符串实际上是24个字符加上空指针
So uh and we'll see why it didn't...it should have crashed
所以呃，我们会明白为什么它没有......它应该崩溃了
Because we actually overwrite wrote the low order byte of the return address
因为我们实际上覆盖了写入返回地址的低位字节
Here we typed in this is 25 characters
这里我们输入的是25个字符
And so that's the one I just showed where it really whacked the two bytes of the return address
这就是我刚才展示的那个它真正打击了返回地址的两个字节的地方
So here we actually did overflow the buffer
所以这里我们确实溢出了缓冲区
And let's try and figure out why that didn't harm the the program execution
让我们试着弄清楚为什么这不会损害程序的执行
I see a question
我看到一个问题
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Yes it could have been various other things could have there's nothing
是的它可能是其他各种事情可能没有什么
It hit a segmentation fault
它遇到了分段错误
It probably went to some weird part of the code and just started executing some random stuff
它可能去了一些奇怪的代码部分，并开始执行一些随机的东西
And just got itself into trouble
然后就陷入了麻烦
But that's the point is it's not predictable exactly what will happen when you do this
但重点是，当你这样做时，确切地说会发生什么是不可预测的
So this is that the example of what actually happened the first time
所以这就是第一次实际发生的事例
When I typed in a string that had 24 characters
当我输入一个包含24个字符的字符串时
And so this null byte at the end actually corrupted the return address
所以最后这个空字节实际上破坏了返回地址
And so it was supposed to return back to this address 0x4006f6
所以它应该返回到这个地址0x4006f6
And instead it will return back to the address 0x400600
而它将返回到地址0x400600
Which happens to be in some other weird function that's there
这恰好出现在其他一些奇怪的功能中
And it just sort of landed at some place here
它只是落在这里的某个地方
And it's doing various things but somehow it didn't really (didn't) crash the program
它正在做各种各样的事情，但不知何故，它并没有真正（没有）使程序崩溃
And that's one of the frustrating things about this is that things can go wrong in a program
而这令人沮丧的事情之一是，程序中的事情可能会出错
And they don't always cause a crash
而且他们并不总是导致崩溃
And so often a bug that's working there might be doing some weird stuff that you don't even know about
因此，经常在那里工作的bug可能会做一些你甚至不知道的奇怪的东西
So that's all a fine if it's just a way of crashing programs and
如果它只是一种崩溃程序的方式，那就没关系了
I mean that's not great if it's controlling your pacemaker or something like that
我的意思是，如果它控制你的心脏起搏器或类似的东西，那就不好了
But if it's just a homework assignment it's like not a big deal so
但如果它只是一个家庭作业，那就不是什么大不了的事了
But what actually and this is sort of only happened since
但事实上，这种情况只发生在那之后
Attacking became a normal activity which has only been the last 30 years
攻击成为一种正常活动，仅仅是过去30年
Is that it gives an opportunity for a hacker or a attacker to inject code into the program and execute it
是否为黑客或攻击者提供了将代码注入程序并执行它的机会
And that's what's called a code injection attack
这就是所谓的代码注入攻击
And so that the general scheme of it is I have this buffer that I can fill up with whatever bytes I want
因此，它的一般方案是我有这个缓冲区，我可以填写我想要的任何字节
By feeding them to gets or whatever function is doing this copying
通过喂他们获取或任何功能正在进行此复制
And what I can do then is set up and pass to it
然后我可以做的就是设置并传递给它
Some bytes of actually that encode an executable a little bit of executable code
实际上有些字节可编码可执行代码的一些可执行代码
You've seen an object dump it's printing out these byte code representations of instructions
你已经看到了一个对象转储，它打印出这些指令的字节代码表示
So imagine you fed some of those bytes into your string
所以想象一下，你把这些字节中的一些输入到字符串中
You encoded them in the string that you pass to gets
你在传递给它的字符串中对它们进行了编码
And then you might have to add some more sort of padding characters ,that characters whose value doesn't matter
然后你可能需要添加更多类型的填充字符，这些字符的值无关紧要
In order to then get a number back into the position where the return pointer is supposed to be
然后将数字返回到返回指针所在的位置
And so what's call that number B,it's going to be an address
所以叫做B号，它就是一个地址
One of these ones with the you know that represents a stack location
其中一个与你知道代表堆栈位置的那些
And that value B that is the the starting address of the buffer
而那个值B是缓冲区的起始地址
Which happens to be where your exploit code remember this is just executable instructions or stored here
这恰好是你的漏洞利用代码记住这只是可执行指令或存储在此处的地方
So now what will happen is when the program does its return here
所以现在将会发生什么，当程序在这里返回时
It was supposed to return back to wherever it got called from P
它应该回到从P调用的任何地方
This is a typo, P calls Q not the bar
这是一个错字，P称Q不是吧
So it's supposed to return back to P
所以它应该回到P
And we're and the address the return address was stored here
我们和返回地址的地址都存储在这里
But now I've overwritten that return address  with this buffer position
但现在我用这个缓冲区位置覆盖了该返回地址
So what will happen is the the program counter will happily jump to this bar
所以会发生什么是程序计数器会愉快地跳到这个栏
And start executing whatever it encounters which are the instructions that you've inserted
并开始执行它遇到的任何内容，这些是你插入的指令
And by that means then you can inject code into a machine potentially Somewhere else in the internet
通过这种方式，你可以将代码注入到可能位于互联网其他地方的计算机中
If you could set up a scheme like this
如果你可以设置这样的方案
That would feed these bytes into that machine
这会将这些字节输入该机器
And it would read it in with a function like gets
并且它会使用像gets这样的函数来读取它
And then it would try to do its return but it would start executing your code
然后它会尝试返回但它会开始执行你的代码
So that's a classic code injection attack
这是一个典型的代码注入攻击
And in fact in this lab that you're going to start,comes out at midnight
事实上，在你即将开始的这个实验室中，午夜时分出来
It's called the attack lab because you're going to do this yourself for part of the lab
它被称为攻击实验室，因为你将自己为实验室的一部分做这件事
I think you'll find it pretty interesting
我想你会发现它非常有趣
So this used to be a huge problem on programs
所以这曾经是程序上的一个大问题
-yes-so when you're trying to replace read how do you make sure that your new submitted read provides that exact line
-yes-所以当你试图替换读取时如何确保新提交的读取提供了确切的行
Well that's part of the cleverness of being a hacker
那就是成为黑客的聪明之处
You have to make sure it's in the right spot
你必须确保它在正确的位置
But it's that's actually one of the easier parts
但它实际上是更容易的部分之一
Because for example you have to know the binary code To be able to do this or be able to guess
因为例如你必须知道二进制代码才能做到这一点或能够猜测
So for example in that previous one I could tell that it was allocating 24 bytes for that buffer
所以例如在前一个我可以告诉它为该缓冲区分配24个字节
And so if I just made sure that the length of my exploit code plus the padding is 24 bytes
因此，如果我确保我的漏洞利用代码的长度加上填充是24字节
Then right after that comes the return address
然后就在那之后返回地址
So that's actually pretty easy to do
所以这实际上很容易做到
There was certainly how much memory program is that
肯定有多少内存程序
No you have to have access,you have to know what the reason why this works is
不，你必须有访问权限，你必须知道它的工作原因是什么
It works if you have enough knowledge about the operating system that's running at the other end
如果你对在另一端运行的操作系统有足够的了解，它就可以工作
For example you know it's Linux
例如，你知道它是Linux
You know that you can look at you know what GCC tends to allocate for
你知道你可以看看你知道GCC倾向于分配什么
It you somehow have access to information about the code itself
它以某种方式可以访问有关代码本身的信息
Let's you do this
我们你这样做
Oh so anyways this used to be a huge problem
哦，所以无论如何这曾经是一个巨大的问题
And it started way back in 1988 the first internet attack with called the Morris worm
它始于1988年第一次被称为莫里斯蠕虫的互联网攻击
And it at the time the internet was not a very big place
当时互联网并不是一个非常大的地方
And it basically brought down a huge fraction of the machines
它基本上耗尽了很大一部分机器
That were on the internet at the time
那是当时的互联网
Interestingly enough CMU did not fall victim to this attack
有趣的是，CMU并没有成为这次袭击的牺牲品
Because we'd patched already the vulnerabilities that this particular program exploited
因为我们已经修补了这个特定程序利用的漏洞
And that was the cause that the software engineering institute runs an organization called cert the computer emergency response team
这就是软件工程学院运行一个名为cert的计算机应急响应团队的原因
And that team was set up in response to this attack the Morris worm attack
该团队成立是为了应对莫里斯蠕虫攻击这一攻击
We'll also see an interesting example between two companies in m